Benjamin S. Hill Collection
Benjamin S. Hill Collection
1861-1892
Hill, Benjamin S.
43 items (SC)
Civil War letters from cousin E. F. Hill; also letters, documents, and forms of the Masons and Knights Templar, 1875-1892.
149216
Biographical History
Benjamin S. Hill (fl. 1861-1882) was a member of the Knights Templar. A 95° member, Hill was granted the title of Deputy Grand Representative at large in 1884 while living in Illinois.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Benjamin S. Hill Collection contains Civil War Correspondence from two of Hill's relatives, as well as correspondence from members of the Knights Templar. The collection also contains several pieces of Memorabilia relating to the Knights Templar including a calling card for Benjamin S. Hill, certificates, invitations, and a program.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection contains two series: Correspondence and Memorabilia. The Correspondence is arranged by sender and then sorted chronologically.
Subject and Genre Headings
Civil War (U.S.); Military history; Hill, Benjamin S.; Hill, E. F.; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.; Freemasonry.; Correspondence.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Hill, E. F., 02 May 1861-26 Apr 1886; 17 items (Sc 256)
  - Hill, [N.?] A., 13 Dec 1862-08 Jun 1863; 2 items (Sc 256)
  - Mason and Knights Templar, 08 Aug 1877-10 Jun 1892; 16 items (Sc 256)
- Memorabilia
  - Calling card, 1 item (Sc 256)
  - Certificates, 1884; 1885; 2 items (Sc 256)
  - Invitations (Sc 256)
    - Apollo Commandery Knights Templar, 1877; 1 item (Sc 256)
    - Cincinnati Commandery Knights Templar, 1877; 1 item (Sc 256)
    - Hanselmann Commandery Knights Templar, 1877; undated; 2 items (Sc 256)
  - Program for the Triennial Conclave of the Grand Encampment, 1877; 1 item (Sc 256)